# Tyson Lackey

## **Business Intelligence Analyst**

**Address** 1926 W Burnside St. #604 Portland, Oregon 97209

**Phone** 5037780503

E-mail Lackeyt90@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyson-lackey-33622792/

IT Professional with over **5 years** of experience in Logistics & Supply Chain specializing in Business Intelligence Analysis & Development. Skilled analyst who advances the enterprise through strategic planning, collaboration, and creative problem solving.

# **Experience**

#### 2016-09 - present Business Intelligence Analyst

**XPO** Logistics

- Developed and implemented a unified BI solution in SQL and Power BI that has become a primary sales tool for new client acquisition
- Managed support of JIRA Incidents and enhancements
- Primary Power BI development resource for custom client dashboards and standard offerings within the business
- SSRS report writer coordinating with the business and internal stakeholders, authored SQL reports and implemented enhancements.

#### **2013-12 - 2016-08 Business Analyst**

UTi Worldwide Inc. / DSV Global Transport and Logistics

- Coordinated with the business to implement master data solutions, requirements gathering and delivery
- Data Steward for master data management, ensuring data quality and accuracy for data feeding transactional systems across the business
- Managed projects on an agile development team to improve system processes and data quality.
- Assisted with migration efforts after the company acquisition, successfully sunsetted our database.

#### 

Netflix Inc.

- Fielded inbound support calls for customers across the United States
- · Supported in all technical, billing, and marketing
- · Communication focused, active listening, attention to detail, and the ability to context switch quickly
- Maintained a top 3% of performance across all metrics.

### **Education**

2009-09 - 2011-01 Portland State University

Business Administration Major

**2008-09 - 2009-06 Oregon State University** 

• Business Administration Major

#### **Skills**

3	F
Advanced	E
Advanced	-
Intermediate	
Excellent	[